{
  "questions": [
    {
        "id": 1,
        "type": "单词",
        "question": "椅子",
        "answer": "chair",
        "textbook": "NCE1",
        "keyPoint": "单词拼写",
        "ability": "记忆能力"
      },
      {
        "id": 2,
        "type": "单词",
        "question": "海关",
        "answer": "customs",
        "textbook": "NCE1",
        "keyPoint": "单词拼写",
        "ability": "抽象思维"
      },
      {
        "id": 3,
        "type": "单词",
        "question": "书桌",
        "answer": "desk",
        "textbook": "NCE1",
        "keyPoint": "单词拼写",
        "ability": "记忆能力"
      },
      {
        "id": 4,
        "type": "单词",
        "question": "护照",
        "answer": "passport",
        "textbook": "NCE1",
        "keyPoint": "单词拼写",
        "ability": "抽象思维"
      },
      {
        "id": 5,
        "type": "单词",
        "question": "相同的",
        "answer": "same",
        "textbook": "NCE1",
        "keyPoint": "单词拼写",
        "ability": "记忆能力"
      },
      {
        "id": 6,
        "type": "单词",
        "question": "新闻",
        "answer": "news",
        "textbook": "NCE1",
        "keyPoint": "单词拼写",
        "ability": "抽象思维"
      },
      {
        "id": 7,
        "type": "单词",
        "question": "懒的",
        "answer": "lazy",
        "textbook": "NCE1",
        "keyPoint": "单词拼写",
        "ability": "记忆能力"
      },
      {
        "id": 8,
        "type": "单词",
        "question": "工程师",
        "answer": "engineer",
        "textbook": "NCE1",
        "keyPoint": "单词拼写",
        "ability": "抽象思维"
      },
      {
        "id": 9,
        "type": "单词",
        "question": "冰箱",
        "answer": "fridge|refrigerator",
        "textbook": "NCE1",
        "keyPoint": "单词拼写",
        "ability": "记忆能力"
      },
      {
        "id": 10,
        "type": "单词",
        "question": "国籍",
        "answer": "nationality",
        "textbook": "NCE1",
        "keyPoint": "单词拼写",
        "ability": "抽象思维"
      },
      {
        "id": 11,
        "type": "单词",
        "question": "这些",
        "answer": "these",
        "textbook": "",
        "keyPoint": "代词",
        "ability": "词汇理解"
        },
        {
          "id": 12,
          "type": "单词",
          "question": "红色的",
          "answer": "red|reddish",
          "textbook": "",
          "keyPoint": "形容词",
          "ability": "词汇理解"
        },
        {
          "id": 13,
          "type": "单词",
          "question": "灰色的",
          "answer": "gray|grey",
          "textbook": "",
          "keyPoint": "形容词",
          "ability": "词汇理解"
        },
        {
          "id": 14,
          "type": "单词",
          "question": "黄色的",
          "answer": "yellow|yellowish",
          "textbook": "",
          "keyPoint": "形容词",
          "ability": "词汇理解"
        },
        {
          "id": 15,
          "type": "单词",
          "question": "黑色的",
          "answer": "black",
          "textbook": "",
          "keyPoint": "形容词",
          "ability": "词汇理解"
        },
        {
          "id": 16,
          "type": "单词",
          "question": "橘黄色的",
          "answer": "orange",
          "textbook": "",
          "keyPoint": "形容词",
          "ability": "词汇理解"
        },
        {
          "id": 17,
          "type": "单词",
          "question": "雇员",
          "answer": "employee",
          "textbook": "",
          "keyPoint": "名词",
          "ability": "词汇理解"
        },
        {
          "id": 18,
          "type": "单词",
          "question": "勤奋的",
          "answer": "hard-working|diligent",
          "textbook": "",
          "keyPoint": "形容词",
          "ability": "词汇理解"
        },
        {
          "id": 19,
          "type": "单词",
          "question": "推销员",
          "answer": "sales reps|salesperson",
          "textbook": "",
          "keyPoint": "词组",
          "ability": "词汇理解"
        },
        {
          "id": 20,
          "type": "单词",
          "question": "男人",
          "answer": "man|men",
          "textbook": "",
          "keyPoint": "名词",
          "ability": "词汇理解"
        },
        {
          "id": 21,
          "type": "单词",
          "question": "办公室",
          "answer": "office",
          "textbook": "",
          "keyPoint": "名词",
          "ability": "词汇理解"
        },
        {
          "id": 22,
          "type": "单词",
          "question": "助手",
          "answer": "assistant",
          "textbook": "",
          "keyPoint": "名词",
          "ability": "词汇理解"
        },
        {
          "id": 23,
          "type": "单词",
          "question": "事情",
          "answer": "matter",
          "textbook": "",
          "keyPoint": "名词",
          "ability": "词汇理解"
        },
        {
          "id": 24,
          "type": "单词",
          "question": "孩子们",
          "answer": "children|kids",
          "textbook": "",
          "keyPoint": "名词",
          "ability": "词汇理解"
        },
        {
          "id": 25,
          "type": "单词",
          "question": "累，疲乏",
          "answer": "tired",
          "textbook": "",
          "keyPoint": "形容词",
          "ability": "词汇理解"
        },
        {
          "id": 26,
          "type": "单词",
          "question": "男孩",
          "answer": "boy",
          "textbook": "",
          "keyPoint": "名词",
          "ability": "词汇理解"
        },
        {
          "id": 27,
          "type": "单词",
          "question": "妈妈(儿语)",
          "answer": "mum|mom",
          "textbook": "",
          "keyPoint": "名词",
          "ability": "词汇理解"
        },
        {
          "id": 28,
          "type": "单词",
          "question": "坐下",
          "answer": "sit down",
          "textbook": "",
          "keyPoint": "词组",
          "ability": "词汇理解"
        },
        {
          "id": 29,
          "type": "单词",
          "question": "口渴",
          "answer": "thirsty",
          "textbook": "",
          "keyPoint": "形容词",
          "ability": "词汇理解"
        },
        {
          "id": 30,
          "type": "单词",
          "question": "好，可以",
          "answer": "right|ok|alright|fine|okay|good|well",
          "textbook": "",
          "keyPoint": "形容词",
          "ability": "词汇理解"
        },
        {
          "id": 31,
          "type": "单词",
          "question": "冰淇淋",
          "answer": "ice cream",
          "textbook": "",
          "keyPoint": "词组",
          "ability": "词汇理解"
        },
        {
          "id": 32,
          "type": "单词",
          "question": "大的",
          "answer": "big|large",
          "textbook": "",
          "keyPoint": "形容词",
          "ability": "词汇理解"
        },
        {
          "id": 33,
          "type": "单词",
          "question": "小的",
          "answer": "small|little",
          "source": "",
          "keyPoint": "形容词",
          "ability": "词汇理解"
        },
        {
          "id": 34,
          "type": "单词",
          "question": "开着的",
          "answer": "open|opened",
          "textbook": "",
          "keyPoint": "形容词",
          "ability": "词汇理解"
        },
        {
          "id": 35,
          "type": "单词",
          "question": "关着的",
          "answer": "closed|shut",
          "textbook": "",
          "keyPoint": "形容词",
          "ability": "词汇理解"
        },
        {
          "id": 36,
          "type": "单词",
          "question": "轻的",
          "answer": "light|lightweight",
          "textbook": "",
          "keyPoint": "形容词",
          "ability": "词汇理解"
        },
        {
          "id": 37,
          "type": "单词",
          "question": "重的",
          "answer": "heavy|heavyweight",
          "textbook": "",
          "keyPoint": "形容词",
          "ability": "词汇理解"
        },
        {
          "id": 38,
          "type": "单词",
          "question": "长的",
          "answer": "long|lengthy",
          "textbook": "",
          "keyPoint": "形容词",
          "ability": "词汇理解"
        },
        {
          "id": 39,
          "type": "单词",
          "question": "鞋子",
          "answer": "shoes|footwear",
          "textbook": "",
          "keyPoint": "名词",
          "ability": "词汇理解"
        },
        {
          "id": 40,
          "type": "单词",
          "question": "祖父，外祖父",
          "answer": "grandfather|grandpa",
          "textbook": "",
          "keyPoint": "名词",
          "ability": "词汇理解"
        },
        {
          "id": 41,
          "type": "单词",
          "question": "祖母，外祖母",
          "answer": "grandmother|grandma",
          "textbook": "NCE1",
          "keyPoint": "名词",
          "ability": "词汇理解"
        }
  ]
} 